[
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "You should remember that most of the young adults we see can't drive or don't have access to a car, so make sure that you are close to public transportation.",
        "question": "Any thoughts as to how to ensure that adolescents can access the dental clinic we are planning?"
    },

    "id": 7
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "You need to be flexible. Teens will show up late. They will forget what you say. They may say things that seem immature. But it's because they are immature. This period of their lives is such a crucial time when they can adopt either harmful habits or healthy behaviors that will carry with them into adulthood. And they will listen to you. ",
        "question": "What things in particular about young adults in the neighborhood should be we considerate about in our dental program planning?"
    },

    "id": 8
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "You need to remember that most kids here can't just pick up a mixed green salad or drive across town to a farmer's market. I know that many of our youth make poor nutritional choices, but it's also an issue of viable food options. This neighborhood is considered a \"food desert\", an area with limited healthy food options. I know that this ultimately affects their overall health including their teeth. I wonder if there is some way you can incorporate some kind of engagement with local nutritionists or local markets in your program?",
        "question": "How do you think the dental clinic can best serve the local young adults in the neighborhood?"
    },

    "id": 9
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I really don't know. We have tried in the past to get the local youth but we had a hard time with broken appointments. I'm not sure if it was that they couldn't get here or they just didn't care about their teeth but it was a problem for us.",
        "question": "Do you have any suggestions as to how we can make sure young adults easily access the dental clinic?"
    },

    "id": 10
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "It's a tough population to work with. Maybe it's because our practice mostly sees older adults. The few that I have seen have a lot of dental problems and don't have to pay out of pocket. I have either done the work pro bono or referred them to the dental school.",
        "question": "We want to be sure young adults use the dental clinic. Anything in particular we should be mindful of?"
    },

    "id": 11
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "The kids around here have a lot of cavities. And I think you can track that back to what they chose to eat and drink - all the junk food and soda. Ultimately, it comes down to how the local teens and families prioritizing oral health. My door is open all week long, but if you don't care about taking care of your teeth. It's a real problem.",
        "question": "In your opinion, what are the current dental needs of the local adolescents?"
    },

    "id": 12
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I've heard that some programs that target teens have hours that are more suited to their lifestyle. Have you considered holding evening or weekend hours?",
        "question": "We want to make sure young adults can access dental services. Do you have any tips?"
    },

    "id": 13
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "There are a lot of people doing good things in this community, folks that know this neighborhood and have been working here for years. Be sure to actively seek these groups out and form partnerships. That's the best advice I can give you if you want to succeed with the local youth here.",
        "question": "As we plan the dental clinic, how can we best ensure that our services are culturally appropriate?"
    },

    "id": 14
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I know that you are dentist and that from your perspective, it's all about the mouth. It's not that we don't care about our teeth. We value oral health just as much as the next person, but understand that for many us, keeping our jobs, paying the rent, and putting food on the table simply have a higher priority. It's hard to brush your teeth in the dark because you can't pay your electric bill.  ",
        "question": "What do you think are the main dental concerns of the local adolescents?"
    },

    "id": 15
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "In order to be successful here, you need someone here that can provide services consistently. Not sporadically or part-time. Even if you can't provide comprehensive dental services every day, can you have a dental hygienist on the other days to do cleanings, dental screenings, or oral health promotion?",
        "question": "How would you ensure young adults have access to dental services?"
    },

    "id": 16
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Working with teens is different from other populations. They don't fit your traditional models of dental practice. We can't effectively schedule more than 2 weeks out at a time and you absolutely need to be able to accommodate \"walk-in\" patients.",
        "question": "Any cultural considerations we should be aware of while we plan out the dental clinic?"
    },

    "id": 17
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Our patients have a lot of health problems but definitely know that the patients we see have a lot of dental need. They come for sexual health, but we also see cavities and hear them complain about dental pain. Most of all, there is nowhere to go to get all their dental treatment done here.",
        "question": "From your experience, are there any particular dental needs by the local young adults?"
    },

    "id": 18
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Don't take the x-rays and do the check up and THEN give us a slip of paper saying that we now need to go somewhere else. Why couldn't you do it?  We need someone who will take care of problems not tell us to go to someone else across town. I already know I have holes in my teeth. I need someone who will fix them!  ",
        "question": "If you were designing a dental clinic, what steps would you take to ensure that young adults can access its services?"
    },

    "id": 19
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I'm 52 years old and I still hate going to the dentist! Just opening your door and saying you're here won't be enough. You should see how you can partner with other programs in the area that are successful with youth. The high school has programs. So do some churches and the community center I think.",
        "question": "What steps can we take to make sure that the clinic is culturally appropriate to the young adults we are hoping to serve?"
    },

    "id": 20
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "All this junk food in the stores is what is causing all these cavities. If all that liquor and cigarettes were enough.  Close them all down I say. Kids weren't so lazy and fat in my day.",
        "question": "What do you think are the most pressing dental concerns of the adolescents in the community?"
    },

    "id": 21
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Be consistent. This community has had a lot of \"well intended\" disappointments in the past. If you are going to start something, be sure you are committed to it. There is no problem with starting small and building it up. It's worst to promise too much and then fall short.",
        "question": "How can we make sure that the dental services we are planning to provide will be properly accessed by the young adults here?"
    },

    "id": 22
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Remember that teenagers are teenagers. You can want them to act like adults all you want, but they will still behave like teenagers. At some point, you have to meet them where they are if you want to be successful.",
        "question": "We want to make sure our program is culturally appropriate and sensitive to local needs. Any advice?"
    },

    "id": 23
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I'm not sure how this might apply to your dental program, but I have noticed that so many of the youth that I work with have really poor self-image and self-esteem issues.",
        "question": "Have you noticed any issues with the youth that a dental program may be able to address?"
    },

    "id": 24
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "It's one thing to do dental screenings and sealants, but some of the youth have some real big dental problems. How are you going to handle extractions? Or root canals? How will you handle an emergency walk-in with facial swelling? You need to develop your policy for emergencies and referrals.",
        "question": "What professional guidelines do you think we need to be especially mindful of?"
    },

    "id": 25
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I think that it's important to have a system in place to address how minors will be seen in your program. I think it's great that you want to give back, but be careful about liability. Even if you have the best intentions, you don't want to be caught treating a 15 year old without their parent knowing. ",
        "question": "Any advice as to how to ensure the proper provision of and eligibility for services?"
    },

    "id": 26
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "When we were starting up the AHC, one of the biggest issues that we faced was determining exactly what type of services we were going to provide to our youth. I'm not sure how that is determined in dentistry.",
        "question": "Are there any new policies or guidelines regarding adolescents that we should keep in mind?"
    },

    "id": 27
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Our administrative staff at the AHC are fantastic about finding out which services can be reimbursed, and its our social workers who are responsible to assist the uninsured in receiving coverage they are eligible for. It takes a lot of communication but it works. ",
        "question": "How can we take steps to make sure that all young adults are eligible for our dental services?"
    },

    "id": 28
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I'm sure you know about the considerations regarding HIPAA and confidentiality, but whenever you are dealing with adolescents, especially underage minors, you have to pay special attention to consent and issues of privacy. Often our clients don't want anyone to know that they were here, including their parents, which makes things challenging.",
        "question": "We want to make sure that our program is consistent with current guidelines for adolescents. Anything in particular we should be aware of?"
    },

    "id": 29
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I don't know too much about this. But almost all of our clients qualify for Medicaid or have coverage under their parent's insurance. I heard that also includes dental.",
        "question": "We know that eligibility for dental services can be an issue. Any thoughts are how we can avoid issues with this?"
    },

    "id": 30
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I don't know what you have at the clinic but we tried to institute a \"3 strikes and you're out\" policy for some of our after school programs to try to create some personal accountability. But a lot of times it ended up being more like 5 or 6 strikes. Teens are just really undependable.",
        "question": "Are you aware of any policies or guidelines that we should be mindful of as we plan our clinic?"
    },

    "id": 31
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "You should make sure that you have policy in place for special youth populations, like emancipated minors, as we do have a few situations in our community where a teen is allowed to sign for his/her own consent.",
        "question": "Any recommendations regarding eligibility for dental services as we make our preparations?"
    },

    "id": 32
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Aren't the standards for teenagers the same as for adults? You need to ask someone who knows this stuff. That person is not me.",
        "question": "Any recommendations regarding standards of care for young adults?"
    },

    "id": 33
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "I don't know. Maybe you should try talking to one of the doctors at the AHC or a dentist for this sort of thing.",
        "question": "We want to make sure that every young adult that comes to the program is eligible for services. Do you foresee any problems?"
    },

    "id": 34
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Sorry. I don't know anything about that. Running a small business and volleyball is my area of expertise.",
        "question": "Any specific guidelines for adolescents to keep in mind as we move forward?"
    },

    "id": 35
},
{
    "fields": {
        "answer": "Have you considered how you will get consent for minors for any treatment? We had such a hard time just to get permission for them to be part of the team. And isn't health care information confidential? How would you address that? Oops, sorry ... those were questions and you wanted advice!",
        "question": "We want to be sure that everyone coming is eligible for services. Any suggestions?"
    },
    "id": 36
}
]
